<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Opinion &#8211; practiceblog</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/category/opinion/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>A project by Antu Roy</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2020 19:25:53 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.5.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/cropped-download-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Opinion &#8211; practiceblog</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>“Go to HAEFA!”</title>
		<link>/index.php/2020/10/10/go-to-haefa/</link>
					<comments>/index.php/2020/10/10/go-to-haefa/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[user_blog]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2020 19:25:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Opinion]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=16</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A self-effacing man, Ruhul Abid was moved by the poor state of healthcare services at the Rohingya camps in Cox’s Bazar. This physician extraordinaire and his organisation HAEFA have set up an efficient high-tech healthcare system in Kutupalong and Balukhali camps and have many more plans in the pipeline. Having passed out from Dhaka Medical College, Ruhul Abid went on to obtain a PhD degree in molecular biology from]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>A self-effacing man, Ruhul Abid was moved by the poor state of healthcare services at the Rohingya camps in Cox’s Bazar. This physician extraordinaire and his organisation HAEFA have set up an efficient high-tech healthcare system in Kutupalong and Balukhali camps and have many more plans in the pipeline. Having passed out from Dhaka Medical College, Ruhul Abid went on to obtain a PhD degree in molecular biology from Japan, then completed a fellowship in vascular medicine at Harvard University and is presently an associate professor of cardiothoracic surgery and a faculty member at the Rhode Island Hospital and the Alpert Medical School of Brown University in the US. He spoke to Prothom Alo about what HAEFA has achieved at the refugee camps and his vision for the future.</p>



<p><strong>Prothom Alo:</strong> You and your organisation HAEFA have set up an efficient digitalised healthcare system in a number of Rohingya refugee camps in Cox’s Bazar. How did it all start?</p>



<p><strong>Ruhul Abid:</strong> I was already involved in a project providing health services to women workers of the readymade garments industry.&nbsp; [See:&lt;https://en.prothomalo.com/economy/news/178152/Taking-health-to-the-RMG-workers&gt;] Then last year, in July 2017, I came on a visit to Cox’s Bazar with my wife and daughter. On our way to Teknaf by the Marine Drive, I noticed slums by the roadside and inquired about this. I was told Rohingyas lived here. They had come to Bangladesh from as far back as 1990, 2012, 2016 and then there was the fifth exodus from August last year.</p>



<p>I wondered what could be done. I realised if I was to do anything for them, I would need funds and so set to task upon my return to the US. I first received a donation of US$7000 from a mosque in Boston where I live. That would cover two camps for at least one month. I contacted young doctors in Bangladesh and returned. We set up two simple centres comprising four bamboos and a cover overhead, sharing space with the government centres at the Kutupalong and Baulkhali camps. We rented apartments for our four doctors, six nurses and eight health workers and also rented a 12-seater van.&nbsp; That is how it all started.</p>



<p><strong>Prothom Alo:</strong> So what sort of health services have you been providing and how is it any different from the existing government health services?</p>



<p><strong>Ruhul Abid:</strong> We have an organisation called HAEFA &#8211; Health and Education for All, founded by myself and Rosemary Duda of Harvard Medical School. So as a HAEFA initiative, we started running these centres which began functioning on 9 October last year. We were to introduce ournovel electronic medical record system (called NIROG) there where patients first went to one table where their height and weight were taken and entered into a tab where their BMI was also calculated and recorded. At the next table their blood pressure and heart rate was measured and entered into a tab. At the third table their blood sugar and haemoglobin count was measured and also entered. The doctor at the fourth table simply opens a port on his/her tab and has access to patient’s details. The main diseases treated are hypertension, diabetes, asthma and tuberculosis. Other ailments treated are anaemia, high risk pregnancies, mental health and more.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://images.prothomalo.com/prothomalo-english%2Fimport%2Fmedia%2F2018%2F07%2F03%2F8b8f0eec78b139696b82a5d10e7f09ad-HAEFA-2.jpg?w=640&amp;auto=format%2Ccompress" alt="An infant being treated at the HAEFA health centre in the refugee camp"/><figcaption>An infant being treated at the HAEFA health centre in the refugee camp</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>Prothom Alo:</strong> What sort of mental health problems do you find among these Rohingya refugees?</p>



<p><strong>Ruhul Abid:</strong> They are suffering from post traumatic stress disorder (PTSD). They have seen their parents killed and other indescribable atrocities. They need counseling. We cannot offer extensive treatment in this context.</p>



<p><strong>Prothom Alo:</strong> Can you tell us more about the hi-tech health check system you have introduced here in the camps and further details?</p>



<p><strong>Ruhul Abid:</strong> We mostly treat non-communicable diseases. These problems include blood pressure, blood glucose, hypertension, diabetes, tuberculosis and such. If tuberculosis is suspected, we refer them to the BRAC centre for sputum test. Now we have developed a referral system. We have trained two girls in the Kutupalong and Balukhali camps. They collect the sputum and take it to the centre.</p>



<p>We use a longitudinal patient tracking system. Each patient is issued a card with a bar code. All details are entered on the card and medication is prescribed accordingly. When they visit the next week, the bar code is scanned and everything shows up. I can see their records sitting in Boston or in Balukhali and can prescribe the next medication accordingly or adjust the dose or whatever.</p>



<p>Another thing is that the patients may lose their cards. After all, given the circumstances in which they live, they have far more pressing concerns that preserving their cards. So we have introduced a fingerprinting system. They just place their finger on the scanner and their records and details show up. At the end of the day when about 300 cases are seen, all data is uploaded in the Azurecloud.</p>



<p>Interestingly, a Canadian doctor communicated with me, wanting to use our records to help them in verifying the accounts of certain refugees who seek entry in Canada, showing gunshot wounds and other assault wounds. Just fingerprint scanning can verify the records. So the potential of this system is vast.</p>



<p><strong>Prothom Alo:</strong> How has the response been from the camp people in terms of number?</p>



<p><strong>Ruhul Abid:</strong> Overwhelming response. From 9 October last year till May this year, we have had a total of 31,000 patients. On average we see around 6,500 to 7,500 patients a month. It is all free of cost.</p>



<p>We are so well established in the two camps now that patients from other camps are sent here. If they are diagnosed to have diabetes or high blood pressure, they are invariably told. “Go to HAEFA!”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/2020/10/10/go-to-haefa/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>High Court verdict: Bold statement against corruption of judges</title>
		<link>/index.php/2020/10/10/high-court-verdict-bold-statement-against-corruption-of-judges/</link>
					<comments>/index.php/2020/10/10/high-court-verdict-bold-statement-against-corruption-of-judges/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[user_blog]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2020 19:23:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Opinion]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=15</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The High Court’s observation against the corruption of the judiciary, especially judges, in a case involving abandoned property is a milestone. In the history of the last 50 years, this was the first time that such a bold and strong statement was made against the corruption committed by the judges. The two authors of the judgment along with the entire Supreme Court should be congratulated for this.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The High Court’s observation against the corruption of the judiciary, especially judges, in a case involving abandoned property is a milestone. In the history of the last 50 years, this was the first time that such a bold and strong statement was made against the corruption committed by the judges. The two authors of the judgment along with the entire Supreme Court should be congratulated for this.</p>



<p>With deep confidence and conviction, we would like to assume that such an anti-corruption attitude is an expression of the mind of all sincere judges. Though it may sound unpleasant, but frank expressions like ‘sale of judgment’ or ‘unscrupulous, rotten and corrupt judges will slowly destroy good judges’ were expected earlier. But it is better late than never.</p>



<p>The perception of the court is very realistic that the people get angry and upset and search for alternatives if there is no justice in the court and if &#8216;justice&#8217; is tainted by corruption. The court has also identified the root cause of the society becoming so dependent on terror and muscle power. The court said that the people want justice from bullies and ‘mafia leaders’ as the court does not deliver justice. Advertisement</p>



<p>However, all the concerned in the state must take proper steps, in keeping with the steps identified in the observation. The beginning of some of these significant steps is in the hands of the judiciary. But we have observed with concern that whenever the name of any judge has come up or been hinted at, sensitivity has been displayed by the judiciary. The main responsibility now lies with the judiciary to make it clear that speaking or reporting over the corruption of the judiciary on the basis of specific evidence is not the same as ‘scandalising the court’. <a target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://en.prothomalo.com/opinion/Independent-judiciary-can-stop-quashing">Also ReadIndependent judiciary can stop quashing &#8216;political&#8217; cases</a></p>



<p>Another crucial opinion of the court is, “News was discussed in the society and among the intellectual circles and published in the media seeking independence of the judiciary. But no specific or clear report, writing or research on how to throw the corrupt judges away from the lower courts to the higher ones was visible.” In this case, we need to clarify our position as a media.Advertisement</p>



<p>The constitution specifically rests the power to conduct the preliminary investigations into the corruption of the lower court judges and to recommend their removal if proven guilty with the High Court. But for years, we have seen that the High Court division has been slow and unconcerned regarding the investigations into the corruption of the lower court judges. And we have not been able to practice such freedom of expression to say the higher court judges are involved in corruption. From that consideration, this verdict has opened an unprecedented opportunity to open the eyes of all concerned and to make them introspect.</p>



<p>Prior to the 16th amendment, the Supreme Judicial Council headed by the chief justice and the next two senior justices had been inactive for almost several decades. The rules of procedure for the council itself have not even been introduced. It is natural that there would be an impact of this on the higher courts. The council has been revived by repealing the 16th amendment. A year ago, two justices were deservedly suspended for writing ‘judgment’ through corruption. But the process did not proceed further. It is imperative to end such situation.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/2020/10/10/high-court-verdict-bold-statement-against-corruption-of-judges/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
