<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Bangladesh &#8211; practiceblog</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/category/bangladesh/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>A project by Antu Roy</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2020 19:10:11 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.5.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/cropped-download-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Bangladesh &#8211; practiceblog</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Shoe factory catches fire in Gazipur</title>
		<link>/index.php/2020/10/10/shoe-factory-catches-fire-in-gazipur/</link>
					<comments>/index.php/2020/10/10/shoe-factory-catches-fire-in-gazipur/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[user_blog]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2020 19:10:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Bangladesh]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=10</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>A shoe factory in Gazipur has caught fire on Saturday afternoon.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Five units of fire fighters are working to douse the fire which ensued in FB Footware Limited in Kaliakair upazila’s Ulusara area.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>A shoe factory in Gazipur has caught fire on Saturday afternoon.</p>



<p>Five units of fire fighters are working to douse the fire which ensued in FB Footware Limited in Kaliakair upazila’s Ulusara area.</p>



<p>Fire service and factory authorities said chemical substances for shoemaking were stored at one side of the one-storey factory building.Advertisement</p>



<p>The authorities think that the fire broke out from those chemicals at around 4:30pm.</p>



<p>Kaliakair fire service and civil defence’s station officer Md Kabirul Islam said the reason of the fire cannot be ascertained now but they suspect that the fire ensued from chemical substances.</p>



<p>No casualty has been reported yet.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/2020/10/10/shoe-factory-catches-fire-in-gazipur/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Anti-rape protests around the country keep up momentum</title>
		<link>/index.php/2020/10/10/anti-rape-protests-around-the-country-keep-up-momentum/</link>
					<comments>/index.php/2020/10/10/anti-rape-protests-around-the-country-keep-up-momentum/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[user_blog]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2020 19:08:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Bangladesh]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=9</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Activists of different organisations, including those working on women's rights, staged demonstrations on the road in front of the Jatiya Sangsad on Saturday, protesting the growing incidents of rape and demanding the toughest punishment for rapists, reports UNB.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Activists of different organisations, including those working on women&#8217;s rights, staged demonstrations on the road in front of the Jatiya Sangsad on Saturday, protesting the growing incidents of rape and demanding the toughest punishment for rapists, reports UNB.<br><br>The protesters were chanting various slogans condemning the &#8216;impunity of rapists&#8217; and demanding prompt action to bring the rapists to book.<br><br>They were holding placards inscribed with: &#8220;Stop protecting rapists&#8221;, &#8220;Mukti chai, Rokkha Noi&#8221;.<br><br>Protests against the growing incidents of rape, sexual harassment and violence against women are continuing in different parts of the country.<br><br>The protesters included general people and leaders and activists from different organisations.<br><br>The recent incident of gang rape at Sylhet MC College and a housewife&#8217;s molestation in Begumganj of Noakhali fueled the protests.<br><br>Some protesters also called for the resignation of home minister Asaduzzaman Khan Kamal over the government&#8217;s &#8216;failure&#8217; to rein in the alarming rise in sexual violence against women and girls in the country.<br><br>Advertisement</p>



<p><a target="_blank" href="https://en.prothomalo.com/bangladesh/government/death-penalty-for-rape-ministry-sending-amendments-to-cabinet" rel="noreferrer noopener">The law minister on Thursday said </a>they are putting forward a proposal for bringing an amendment to the relevant law with a provision for awarding death penalty to a rapist as the highest punishment instead of life imprisonment.<br><br>A group of feminists under the banner &#8216;Feminists across Generations&#8217; however, rejected the law minister&#8217;s proposal, asserting that the death penalty for rape cannot be a solution when the problem is that 97 per cent of cases filed over violence against women, including rape, don&#8217;t even result in a conviction.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/2020/10/10/anti-rape-protests-around-the-country-keep-up-momentum/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
