<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>practiceblog</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>A project by Antu Roy</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2020 19:32:18 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.5.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/cropped-download-32x32.png</url>
	<title>practiceblog</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Veteran actor Soumitra Chatterjee&#8217;s condition worsens, shifted to ICU</title>
		<link>/index.php/2020/10/10/veteran-actor-soumitra-chatterjees-condition-worsens-shifted-to-icu/</link>
					<comments>/index.php/2020/10/10/veteran-actor-soumitra-chatterjees-condition-worsens-shifted-to-icu/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[user_blog]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2020 19:32:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Entertainment]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=19</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Veteran Bengali actor Soumitra Chatterjee was shifted to Intensive Care Unit in a private hospital late Friday night after the 85-year-old's health deteriorated, hospital sources said on Saturday.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Veteran Bengali actor Soumitra Chatterjee was shifted to Intensive Care Unit in a private hospital late Friday night after the 85-year-old&#8217;s health deteriorated, hospital sources said on Saturday.</p>



<p>Chatterjee, who had tested coronavirus positive on 5 October, was suffering from several comorbidities. He was immediately shifted to an ICU for close monitoring.</p>



<p>A day after his COVID-19 test on 5 October gave positive report, he was admitted to the hospital but in a stable condition.Advertisement</p>



<p>The sources said Chatterjee was unwell for the past couple of days and reportedly suffering from fever. He was shooting for a documentary titled &#8216;Abhijan&#8217; directed by actor Parambrata Chattopadhyay.</p>



<p>He had attended the shoot floor at Bharatlaxmi Studio on 1 October. The next shooting schedule was on 7 October.<a target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://en.prothomalo.com/entertainment/Soumitra-Chatterjee-conferred-France%E2%80%99s-highest">Also ReadSoumitra Chatterjee conferred France’s highest civilian award</a></p>



<p>It was learnt that the actor had chronic obstructive pulmonary disease-related problem. Last year, he had suffered a bout of pneumonia and was admitted to a hospital for a few days.</p>



<p>Earlier, many actors, directors and producers like Ranjit Mallick, his daughter and actress Koel Mallick, wife Dipa Mallick, producer Nispal Singh and director Raj Chakraborty had tested coronavirus positive but have since recovered.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/2020/10/10/veteran-actor-soumitra-chatterjees-condition-worsens-shifted-to-icu/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Impact of coronavirus on higher education in India and Bangladesh</title>
		<link>/index.php/2020/10/10/impact-of-coronavirus-on-higher-education-in-india-and-bangladesh/</link>
					<comments>/index.php/2020/10/10/impact-of-coronavirus-on-higher-education-in-india-and-bangladesh/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[user_blog]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2020 19:30:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Youth]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=18</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A three-day virtual international webinar, 'Living with Covid-19: Impact on Higher Education in India and Bangladesh,' began on Saturday.

The webinar is jointly organised by Jagannath University's Institute of Education and Research (IER), Council for Teacher Education Foundation (CTEF) of Bangladesh and Council of Educational Administration and Management (CEAM) of India. Advertisement]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>A three-day virtual international webinar, &#8216;Living with Covid-19: Impact on Higher Education in India and Bangladesh,&#8217; began on Saturday.<br><br>The webinar is jointly organised by Jagannath University&#8217;s Institute of Education and Research (IER), Council for Teacher Education Foundation (CTEF) of Bangladesh and Council of Educational Administration and Management (CEAM) of India. Advertisement</p>



<p>The webinar will run on Saturday, Sunday and Monday from 9:30 am Bangladesh time, 9:00 am India time to 3:00 pm Bangladesh time and 2:30 pm India time using the Zoom video conferencing app. About 50 research papers will be presented during the three-day webinar.<br><br>Professor Monira Jahan, General Convener of the Organising Committee of the Webinar and Director of the Institute of Education and Research, Jagannath University, told Prothom Alo that the webinar explained how higher education in India and Bangladesh, like the higher education system in the developed world, can be kept afloat in times of emergency. And interactive experiences on various issues of crisis were discussed at the webinar.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/2020/10/10/impact-of-coronavirus-on-higher-education-in-india-and-bangladesh/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>WB’s growth projection not consistent with Bangladesh economic recovery: Minister</title>
		<link>/index.php/2020/10/10/wbs-growth-projection-not-consistent-with-bangladesh-economic-recovery-minister/</link>
					<comments>/index.php/2020/10/10/wbs-growth-projection-not-consistent-with-bangladesh-economic-recovery-minister/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[user_blog]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2020 19:28:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Business]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=17</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Finance minister AHM Mustafa Kamal on Friday said that the World Bank’s latest growth projection is inconsistent with the current economic recovery of Bangladesh.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Finance minister AHM Mustafa Kamal on Friday said that the World Bank’s latest growth projection is inconsistent with the current economic recovery of Bangladesh.</p>



<p>“World Bank is a global financial institution. When it reveals any data or info regarding a country or on any issue, then it can influence everyone for certain reason. The projection that the World Bank gave yesterday regarding Bangladesh’s GDP growth is inconsistent with the country’s current economic recovery,&#8221; said the minister in a press release.Advertisement</p>



<p>The finance minister’s remarks came in the wake of the latest ‘South Asia Economic Focus 2020’ released by the World Bank Thursday.</p>



<p>The Washington-based lending agency projected that the Bangladesh’s GDP growth would likely to be 1.6 per cent in the current fiscal year (FY21) and 3.4 per cent in the next fiscal year (FY22).</p>



<p>Kamal said whatever the World Bank is saying about the country’s current growth status is not new as they have been revealing such numbers since there has been slowdown in the economy due to Novel Coronavirus (COVID-19) pandemic. “They (WB) are still stuck in the same position (regarding projection),” he added.</p>



<p>The finance minister mentioned that despite enough pressure on the health and pandemic operations management, the timely and appropriate stimulus packages of the government alongside social safety measures have strengthened the economy while basic services and goods have also been ensured for the poor section of people.</p>



<p>Bangladesh is now in a very capable position in almost all areas including private and public investment, public expenditure, export earnings and inward remittance flow, he added.Advertisementhttps://4e5b86fb0632233297d23ed0aa358fa8.safeframe.googlesyndication.com/safeframe/1-0-37/html/container.html</p>



<p>Turning again to the projection of the World Bank, the finance minister said it is known to all that the characteristics of the projection of the World Bank is very much ‘conservative method’ and if anyone makes a list of their all recent projections, then it would be found that their projections are far away from reality.</p>



<p>In this regard, Kamal said the government sets its target as per its capacity and thus attains it. “By attaining, we’ll have to prove time and again that we are correct. Again this time, we’ll prove that our target is right through attaining it.”</p>



<p>He also noted that the two per cent cash incentive on remittance through legal channel has increased its flow in the country.</p>



<p>Reiterating that the people of the country is the lifeline of the economy, the finance minister said they would again prove that the World Bank’s projection is inconsistent.Advertisement</p>



<p>He said whatever the prime minister had set the growth target in the budget based on her belief on the country’s people, would be achievable.</p>



<p>“We believe that with the united efforts of all, we’ll be able to attain that target, Insha Allah. Bangladesh was on top of attaining GDP growth over the last 10 years and we hope such trend will continue in the future,” he added.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/2020/10/10/wbs-growth-projection-not-consistent-with-bangladesh-economic-recovery-minister/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>“Go to HAEFA!”</title>
		<link>/index.php/2020/10/10/go-to-haefa/</link>
					<comments>/index.php/2020/10/10/go-to-haefa/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[user_blog]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2020 19:25:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Opinion]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=16</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A self-effacing man, Ruhul Abid was moved by the poor state of healthcare services at the Rohingya camps in Cox’s Bazar. This physician extraordinaire and his organisation HAEFA have set up an efficient high-tech healthcare system in Kutupalong and Balukhali camps and have many more plans in the pipeline. Having passed out from Dhaka Medical College, Ruhul Abid went on to obtain a PhD degree in molecular biology from]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>A self-effacing man, Ruhul Abid was moved by the poor state of healthcare services at the Rohingya camps in Cox’s Bazar. This physician extraordinaire and his organisation HAEFA have set up an efficient high-tech healthcare system in Kutupalong and Balukhali camps and have many more plans in the pipeline. Having passed out from Dhaka Medical College, Ruhul Abid went on to obtain a PhD degree in molecular biology from Japan, then completed a fellowship in vascular medicine at Harvard University and is presently an associate professor of cardiothoracic surgery and a faculty member at the Rhode Island Hospital and the Alpert Medical School of Brown University in the US. He spoke to Prothom Alo about what HAEFA has achieved at the refugee camps and his vision for the future.</p>



<p><strong>Prothom Alo:</strong> You and your organisation HAEFA have set up an efficient digitalised healthcare system in a number of Rohingya refugee camps in Cox’s Bazar. How did it all start?</p>



<p><strong>Ruhul Abid:</strong> I was already involved in a project providing health services to women workers of the readymade garments industry.&nbsp; [See:&lt;https://en.prothomalo.com/economy/news/178152/Taking-health-to-the-RMG-workers&gt;] Then last year, in July 2017, I came on a visit to Cox’s Bazar with my wife and daughter. On our way to Teknaf by the Marine Drive, I noticed slums by the roadside and inquired about this. I was told Rohingyas lived here. They had come to Bangladesh from as far back as 1990, 2012, 2016 and then there was the fifth exodus from August last year.</p>



<p>I wondered what could be done. I realised if I was to do anything for them, I would need funds and so set to task upon my return to the US. I first received a donation of US$7000 from a mosque in Boston where I live. That would cover two camps for at least one month. I contacted young doctors in Bangladesh and returned. We set up two simple centres comprising four bamboos and a cover overhead, sharing space with the government centres at the Kutupalong and Baulkhali camps. We rented apartments for our four doctors, six nurses and eight health workers and also rented a 12-seater van.&nbsp; That is how it all started.</p>



<p><strong>Prothom Alo:</strong> So what sort of health services have you been providing and how is it any different from the existing government health services?</p>



<p><strong>Ruhul Abid:</strong> We have an organisation called HAEFA &#8211; Health and Education for All, founded by myself and Rosemary Duda of Harvard Medical School. So as a HAEFA initiative, we started running these centres which began functioning on 9 October last year. We were to introduce ournovel electronic medical record system (called NIROG) there where patients first went to one table where their height and weight were taken and entered into a tab where their BMI was also calculated and recorded. At the next table their blood pressure and heart rate was measured and entered into a tab. At the third table their blood sugar and haemoglobin count was measured and also entered. The doctor at the fourth table simply opens a port on his/her tab and has access to patient’s details. The main diseases treated are hypertension, diabetes, asthma and tuberculosis. Other ailments treated are anaemia, high risk pregnancies, mental health and more.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://images.prothomalo.com/prothomalo-english%2Fimport%2Fmedia%2F2018%2F07%2F03%2F8b8f0eec78b139696b82a5d10e7f09ad-HAEFA-2.jpg?w=640&amp;auto=format%2Ccompress" alt="An infant being treated at the HAEFA health centre in the refugee camp"/><figcaption>An infant being treated at the HAEFA health centre in the refugee camp</figcaption></figure>



<p><strong>Prothom Alo:</strong> What sort of mental health problems do you find among these Rohingya refugees?</p>



<p><strong>Ruhul Abid:</strong> They are suffering from post traumatic stress disorder (PTSD). They have seen their parents killed and other indescribable atrocities. They need counseling. We cannot offer extensive treatment in this context.</p>



<p><strong>Prothom Alo:</strong> Can you tell us more about the hi-tech health check system you have introduced here in the camps and further details?</p>



<p><strong>Ruhul Abid:</strong> We mostly treat non-communicable diseases. These problems include blood pressure, blood glucose, hypertension, diabetes, tuberculosis and such. If tuberculosis is suspected, we refer them to the BRAC centre for sputum test. Now we have developed a referral system. We have trained two girls in the Kutupalong and Balukhali camps. They collect the sputum and take it to the centre.</p>



<p>We use a longitudinal patient tracking system. Each patient is issued a card with a bar code. All details are entered on the card and medication is prescribed accordingly. When they visit the next week, the bar code is scanned and everything shows up. I can see their records sitting in Boston or in Balukhali and can prescribe the next medication accordingly or adjust the dose or whatever.</p>



<p>Another thing is that the patients may lose their cards. After all, given the circumstances in which they live, they have far more pressing concerns that preserving their cards. So we have introduced a fingerprinting system. They just place their finger on the scanner and their records and details show up. At the end of the day when about 300 cases are seen, all data is uploaded in the Azurecloud.</p>



<p>Interestingly, a Canadian doctor communicated with me, wanting to use our records to help them in verifying the accounts of certain refugees who seek entry in Canada, showing gunshot wounds and other assault wounds. Just fingerprint scanning can verify the records. So the potential of this system is vast.</p>



<p><strong>Prothom Alo:</strong> How has the response been from the camp people in terms of number?</p>



<p><strong>Ruhul Abid:</strong> Overwhelming response. From 9 October last year till May this year, we have had a total of 31,000 patients. On average we see around 6,500 to 7,500 patients a month. It is all free of cost.</p>



<p>We are so well established in the two camps now that patients from other camps are sent here. If they are diagnosed to have diabetes or high blood pressure, they are invariably told. “Go to HAEFA!”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/2020/10/10/go-to-haefa/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>High Court verdict: Bold statement against corruption of judges</title>
		<link>/index.php/2020/10/10/high-court-verdict-bold-statement-against-corruption-of-judges/</link>
					<comments>/index.php/2020/10/10/high-court-verdict-bold-statement-against-corruption-of-judges/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[user_blog]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2020 19:23:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Opinion]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=15</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The High Court’s observation against the corruption of the judiciary, especially judges, in a case involving abandoned property is a milestone. In the history of the last 50 years, this was the first time that such a bold and strong statement was made against the corruption committed by the judges. The two authors of the judgment along with the entire Supreme Court should be congratulated for this.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The High Court’s observation against the corruption of the judiciary, especially judges, in a case involving abandoned property is a milestone. In the history of the last 50 years, this was the first time that such a bold and strong statement was made against the corruption committed by the judges. The two authors of the judgment along with the entire Supreme Court should be congratulated for this.</p>



<p>With deep confidence and conviction, we would like to assume that such an anti-corruption attitude is an expression of the mind of all sincere judges. Though it may sound unpleasant, but frank expressions like ‘sale of judgment’ or ‘unscrupulous, rotten and corrupt judges will slowly destroy good judges’ were expected earlier. But it is better late than never.</p>



<p>The perception of the court is very realistic that the people get angry and upset and search for alternatives if there is no justice in the court and if &#8216;justice&#8217; is tainted by corruption. The court has also identified the root cause of the society becoming so dependent on terror and muscle power. The court said that the people want justice from bullies and ‘mafia leaders’ as the court does not deliver justice. Advertisement</p>



<p>However, all the concerned in the state must take proper steps, in keeping with the steps identified in the observation. The beginning of some of these significant steps is in the hands of the judiciary. But we have observed with concern that whenever the name of any judge has come up or been hinted at, sensitivity has been displayed by the judiciary. The main responsibility now lies with the judiciary to make it clear that speaking or reporting over the corruption of the judiciary on the basis of specific evidence is not the same as ‘scandalising the court’. <a target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://en.prothomalo.com/opinion/Independent-judiciary-can-stop-quashing">Also ReadIndependent judiciary can stop quashing &#8216;political&#8217; cases</a></p>



<p>Another crucial opinion of the court is, “News was discussed in the society and among the intellectual circles and published in the media seeking independence of the judiciary. But no specific or clear report, writing or research on how to throw the corrupt judges away from the lower courts to the higher ones was visible.” In this case, we need to clarify our position as a media.Advertisement</p>



<p>The constitution specifically rests the power to conduct the preliminary investigations into the corruption of the lower court judges and to recommend their removal if proven guilty with the High Court. But for years, we have seen that the High Court division has been slow and unconcerned regarding the investigations into the corruption of the lower court judges. And we have not been able to practice such freedom of expression to say the higher court judges are involved in corruption. From that consideration, this verdict has opened an unprecedented opportunity to open the eyes of all concerned and to make them introspect.</p>



<p>Prior to the 16th amendment, the Supreme Judicial Council headed by the chief justice and the next two senior justices had been inactive for almost several decades. The rules of procedure for the council itself have not even been introduced. It is natural that there would be an impact of this on the higher courts. The council has been revived by repealing the 16th amendment. A year ago, two justices were deservedly suspended for writing ‘judgment’ through corruption. But the process did not proceed further. It is imperative to end such situation.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/2020/10/10/high-court-verdict-bold-statement-against-corruption-of-judges/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Djokovic resists gallant Tsitsipas, sets up Nadal final</title>
		<link>/index.php/2020/10/10/djokovic-resists-gallant-tsitsipas-sets-up-nadal-final/</link>
					<comments>/index.php/2020/10/10/djokovic-resists-gallant-tsitsipas-sets-up-nadal-final/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[user_blog]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2020 19:20:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Sports]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=14</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Top seed Novak Djokovic resisted a valiant and inspired fightback from Stefanos Tsitsipas to set up a French Open final showdown with old rival Rafa Nadal on Friday, winning a near four-hour battle 6-3 6-2 5-7 4-6 6-1.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Top seed Novak Djokovic resisted a valiant and inspired fightback from Stefanos Tsitsipas to set up a French Open final showdown with old rival Rafa Nadal on Friday, winning a near four-hour battle 6-3 6-2 5-7 4-6 6-1.</p>



<p>Showing no sign of the physical problems that troubled him during his previous match, Djokovic was initially dominant and poised for a routine win when he had a match point at 5-4 in the third set.</p>



<p>But he had not counted on fifth seed Tsitsipas’s incredible spirit as the 22-year-old fought his way back into contention with some dazzling shot-making.</p>



<p>Tsitsipas stole the third set as Djokovic faltered then staved off countless break points in the fourth before dragging the match into an unlikely decider.Advertisement</p>



<p>His dream of becoming the first Greek player to reach a Grand Slam final faded away as Djokovic calmly re-asserted his authority against a physically-struggling opponent.</p>



<p>Djokovic sealed victory with a forehand winner, nearly two hours after his first match point.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/2020/10/10/djokovic-resists-gallant-tsitsipas-sets-up-nadal-final/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Firmino brace help Brazil score five against Bolivia</title>
		<link>/index.php/2020/10/10/firmino-brace-help-brazil-score-five-against-bolivia/</link>
					<comments>/index.php/2020/10/10/firmino-brace-help-brazil-score-five-against-bolivia/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[user_blog]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2020 19:18:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Sports]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=13</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Brazil had never lost a World Cup qualifier at home, a run that stood at 54 matches going into Friday’s game, and they never looked in danger of losing that record]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Brazil had never lost a World Cup qualifier at home, a run that stood at 54 matches going into Friday’s game, and they never looked in danger of losing that record</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://assets.prothomalo.com/prothomalo/assets/default-author-image-65aeccf65e75d544d490.svg" alt="Reuters"/></figure>



<p><a rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/intent/tweet?url=https%3A%2F%2Fen.prothomalo.com%2Fsports%2Ffootball%2Ffirmino-brace-help-brazil-score-five-against-bolivia&amp;text=Firmino%20brace%20help%20Brazil%20score%20five%20against%20Bolivia&amp;hashtags="></a></p>



<p>Roberto Firmino scored twice and Marquinhos and Philippe Coutinho also got goals as Brazil hammered Bolivia 5-0 in their opening World Cup qualifier in Sao Paulo on Friday.</p>



<p>Brazil had never lost a World Cup qualifier at home, a run that stood at 54 matches going into Friday’s game, and they never looked in danger of losing that record.</p>



<p>Marquinhos put the home side 1-0 up with a header after 16 minutes before Firmino scored after 18 and 49 minutes, both times by getting on the end of low crosses into the penalty box.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/2020/10/10/firmino-brace-help-brazil-score-five-against-bolivia/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Rajapaksa draws Sri Lanka closer to China after summit</title>
		<link>/index.php/2020/10/10/rajapaksa-draws-sri-lanka-closer-to-china-after-summit/</link>
					<comments>/index.php/2020/10/10/rajapaksa-draws-sri-lanka-closer-to-china-after-summit/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[user_blog]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2020 19:14:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[International]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=12</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[China and Sri Lanka plan to restart discussions on a free trade agreement, Sri Lankan president Gotabaya Rajapaksa said on Friday, following a high-level meeting between the two countries.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>China and Sri Lanka plan to restart discussions on a free trade agreement, Sri Lankan president Gotabaya Rajapaksa said on Friday, following a high-level meeting between the two countries.</p>



<p>Seen as close to Beijing, Rajapaksa has appointed several members of his family to top cabinet positions since his party won a commanding majority in August’s parliamentary elections &#8211; including his brother Mahinda, who previously also served as president.</p>



<p>Negotiations on a free trade agreement were last held in 2017.Advertisement</p>



<p>China has been making increasing inroads into South Asia with its Belt and Road Initiative, aimed at financing critical infrastructure in dozens of countries across the world.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>I want to prove that it is not the case and that this large-scale project will help improve the living standards of the people</p></blockquote>



<p>Mahinda Rajapaksa<a target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://www.facebook.com/sharer.php?u=https%3A%2F%2Fen.prothomalo.com%2Finternational%2Fasia%2Frajapaksa-draws-sri-lanka-closer-to-china-after-summit"></a><a target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://twitter.com/intent/tweet?url=https%3A%2F%2Fen.prothomalo.com%2Finternational%2Fasia%2Frajapaksa-draws-sri-lanka-closer-to-china-after-summit&amp;text=I%20want%20to%20prove%20that%20it%20is%20not%20the%20case%20and%20that%20this%20large-scale%20project%20will%20help%20improve%20the%20living%20standards%20of%20the%20peopleMahinda%20Rajapaksa&amp;hashtags="></a></p>



<p>In 2017, Sri Lanka signed over control of a Chinese-financed port and land around it to Beijing after incurring heavy losses, to the alarm of the United States and regional power India.</p>



<p>On Friday, Rajapaksa rejected accusations that China wanted to trap Sri Lanka into mounting debt with the port deal.Advertisement</p>



<p>“Many geo-political analysis interprets this project as a ‘debt trap’ set up by China to gain control over Sri Lankan affairs,” Rajapaksa told the Chines delegation, led by Yang Jiechi, one of China’s top diplomats.</p>



<p>“I want to prove that it is not the case and that this large-scale project will help improve the living standards of the people,” he added.</p>



<p>The countries also agreed to deepen ties in the agriculture, education, tourism, water supply and healthcare sectors, according to a summary of the meeting released by Rajapaksa’s office.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/2020/10/10/rajapaksa-draws-sri-lanka-closer-to-china-after-summit/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Taiwan president calls for ‘meaningful dialogue’ with China</title>
		<link>/index.php/2020/10/10/taiwan-president-calls-for-meaningful-dialogue-with-china/</link>
					<comments>/index.php/2020/10/10/taiwan-president-calls-for-meaningful-dialogue-with-china/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[user_blog]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2020 19:12:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[International]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=11</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Taiwan wants to have “meaningful dialogue” with China on an equal basis, president Tsai Ing-wen said on Saturday, extending an olive branch at a time of heightened military tension with Beijing, which claims the island as sovereign Chinese territory.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Taiwan wants to have “meaningful dialogue” with China on an equal basis, president Tsai Ing-wen said on Saturday, extending an olive branch at a time of heightened military tension with Beijing, which claims the island as sovereign Chinese territory.</p>



<p>Democratic Taiwan has come under increasing pressure from Beijing, which has ramped up air force activity near the island in the past few weeks, including crossing the Taiwan Strait’s sensitive mid line that normally serves as an unofficial buffer zone.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>As long as the Beijing authorities are willing to resolve antagonisms and improve cross-strait relations, while parity and dignity are maintained, we are willing to work together to facilitate meaningful dialogue</p></blockquote>



<p>Tsai Ing-wen, Taiwan president<a target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://www.facebook.com/sharer.php?u=https%3A%2F%2Fen.prothomalo.com%2Finternational%2Fchina%2Ftaiwan-president-calls-for-meaningful-dialogue-with-china"></a><a target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://twitter.com/intent/tweet?url=https%3A%2F%2Fen.prothomalo.com%2Finternational%2Fchina%2Ftaiwan-president-calls-for-meaningful-dialogue-with-china&amp;text=As%20long%20as%20the%20Beijing%20authorities%20are%20willing%20to%20resolve%20antagonisms%20and%20improve%20cross-strait%20relations%2C%20while%20parity%20and%20dignity%20are%20maintained%2C%20we%20are%20willing%20to%20work%20together%20to%20facilitate%20meaningful%20dialogueTsai%20Ing-wen%2C%20Taiwan%20president&amp;hashtags="></a></p>



<p>China says it is responding to “collusion” between Washington and Taipei, angered at growing US support for the self-governed island. Beijing views this a precursor to Taiwan declaring formal independence, a red line for China.Advertisement</p>



<p>Speaking at National Day celebrations, Tsai described the situation in the Taiwan Strait as “quite tense.” This, along with disputes in the South China Sea, a China-India border conflict and China’s crackdown in Hong Kong, showed democracy and peace in the region were facing big challenges, she said.</p>



<p>If Beijing can heed Taiwan’s voice and jointly facilitate reconciliation and peaceful dialogue, regional tension can surely be resolved, she added.</p>



<p>“As long as the Beijing authorities are willing to resolve antagonisms and improve cross-strait relations, while parity and dignity are maintained, we are willing to work together to facilitate meaningful dialogue,” Tsai said.</p>



<p>There was no immediate reaction from China, which cut off a formal talks mechanism in 2016 after she first won office.Advertisementhttps://978719091b5ef461c60b5352c143aebd.safeframe.googlesyndication.com/safeframe/1-0-37/html/container.html</p>



<p>Tsai said she was committed to maintaining stability in the Taiwan Strait, but that this was the responsibility of both sides.</p>



<p>Still, she has made strengthening Taiwan’s armed forces a priority, and said she would keep pushing this, upholding the principle of neither seeking war nor fearing it.</p>



<p>“Our commitment to our sovereignty and democratic values will not change, but we will also maintain strategic flexibility and be responsive to changes,” she said, without elaborating.</p>



<p>The United States has been pushing Taiwan to modernise its military so they can become a “porcupine”, hard for China to attack. Washington, like most countries, has no formal diplomatic ties with Taipei, though it is its strongest global backer.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/2020/10/10/taiwan-president-calls-for-meaningful-dialogue-with-china/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Shoe factory catches fire in Gazipur</title>
		<link>/index.php/2020/10/10/shoe-factory-catches-fire-in-gazipur/</link>
					<comments>/index.php/2020/10/10/shoe-factory-catches-fire-in-gazipur/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[user_blog]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2020 19:10:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Bangladesh]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=10</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>A shoe factory in Gazipur has caught fire on Saturday afternoon.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Five units of fire fighters are working to douse the fire which ensued in FB Footware Limited in Kaliakair upazila’s Ulusara area.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>A shoe factory in Gazipur has caught fire on Saturday afternoon.</p>



<p>Five units of fire fighters are working to douse the fire which ensued in FB Footware Limited in Kaliakair upazila’s Ulusara area.</p>



<p>Fire service and factory authorities said chemical substances for shoemaking were stored at one side of the one-storey factory building.Advertisement</p>



<p>The authorities think that the fire broke out from those chemicals at around 4:30pm.</p>



<p>Kaliakair fire service and civil defence’s station officer Md Kabirul Islam said the reason of the fire cannot be ascertained now but they suspect that the fire ensued from chemical substances.</p>



<p>No casualty has been reported yet.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/2020/10/10/shoe-factory-catches-fire-in-gazipur/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
