<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>International &#8211; practiceblog</title>
	<atom:link href="/index.php/category/international/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>A project by Antu Roy</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2020 19:15:29 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.5.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/cropped-download-32x32.png</url>
	<title>International &#8211; practiceblog</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Rajapaksa draws Sri Lanka closer to China after summit</title>
		<link>/index.php/2020/10/10/rajapaksa-draws-sri-lanka-closer-to-china-after-summit/</link>
					<comments>/index.php/2020/10/10/rajapaksa-draws-sri-lanka-closer-to-china-after-summit/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[user_blog]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2020 19:14:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[International]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=12</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[China and Sri Lanka plan to restart discussions on a free trade agreement, Sri Lankan president Gotabaya Rajapaksa said on Friday, following a high-level meeting between the two countries.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>China and Sri Lanka plan to restart discussions on a free trade agreement, Sri Lankan president Gotabaya Rajapaksa said on Friday, following a high-level meeting between the two countries.</p>



<p>Seen as close to Beijing, Rajapaksa has appointed several members of his family to top cabinet positions since his party won a commanding majority in August’s parliamentary elections &#8211; including his brother Mahinda, who previously also served as president.</p>



<p>Negotiations on a free trade agreement were last held in 2017.Advertisement</p>



<p>China has been making increasing inroads into South Asia with its Belt and Road Initiative, aimed at financing critical infrastructure in dozens of countries across the world.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>I want to prove that it is not the case and that this large-scale project will help improve the living standards of the people</p></blockquote>



<p>Mahinda Rajapaksa<a target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://www.facebook.com/sharer.php?u=https%3A%2F%2Fen.prothomalo.com%2Finternational%2Fasia%2Frajapaksa-draws-sri-lanka-closer-to-china-after-summit"></a><a target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://twitter.com/intent/tweet?url=https%3A%2F%2Fen.prothomalo.com%2Finternational%2Fasia%2Frajapaksa-draws-sri-lanka-closer-to-china-after-summit&amp;text=I%20want%20to%20prove%20that%20it%20is%20not%20the%20case%20and%20that%20this%20large-scale%20project%20will%20help%20improve%20the%20living%20standards%20of%20the%20peopleMahinda%20Rajapaksa&amp;hashtags="></a></p>



<p>In 2017, Sri Lanka signed over control of a Chinese-financed port and land around it to Beijing after incurring heavy losses, to the alarm of the United States and regional power India.</p>



<p>On Friday, Rajapaksa rejected accusations that China wanted to trap Sri Lanka into mounting debt with the port deal.Advertisement</p>



<p>“Many geo-political analysis interprets this project as a ‘debt trap’ set up by China to gain control over Sri Lankan affairs,” Rajapaksa told the Chines delegation, led by Yang Jiechi, one of China’s top diplomats.</p>



<p>“I want to prove that it is not the case and that this large-scale project will help improve the living standards of the people,” he added.</p>



<p>The countries also agreed to deepen ties in the agriculture, education, tourism, water supply and healthcare sectors, according to a summary of the meeting released by Rajapaksa’s office.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/2020/10/10/rajapaksa-draws-sri-lanka-closer-to-china-after-summit/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Taiwan president calls for ‘meaningful dialogue’ with China</title>
		<link>/index.php/2020/10/10/taiwan-president-calls-for-meaningful-dialogue-with-china/</link>
					<comments>/index.php/2020/10/10/taiwan-president-calls-for-meaningful-dialogue-with-china/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[user_blog]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2020 19:12:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[International]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=11</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Taiwan wants to have “meaningful dialogue” with China on an equal basis, president Tsai Ing-wen said on Saturday, extending an olive branch at a time of heightened military tension with Beijing, which claims the island as sovereign Chinese territory.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Taiwan wants to have “meaningful dialogue” with China on an equal basis, president Tsai Ing-wen said on Saturday, extending an olive branch at a time of heightened military tension with Beijing, which claims the island as sovereign Chinese territory.</p>



<p>Democratic Taiwan has come under increasing pressure from Beijing, which has ramped up air force activity near the island in the past few weeks, including crossing the Taiwan Strait’s sensitive mid line that normally serves as an unofficial buffer zone.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>As long as the Beijing authorities are willing to resolve antagonisms and improve cross-strait relations, while parity and dignity are maintained, we are willing to work together to facilitate meaningful dialogue</p></blockquote>



<p>Tsai Ing-wen, Taiwan president<a target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://www.facebook.com/sharer.php?u=https%3A%2F%2Fen.prothomalo.com%2Finternational%2Fchina%2Ftaiwan-president-calls-for-meaningful-dialogue-with-china"></a><a target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://twitter.com/intent/tweet?url=https%3A%2F%2Fen.prothomalo.com%2Finternational%2Fchina%2Ftaiwan-president-calls-for-meaningful-dialogue-with-china&amp;text=As%20long%20as%20the%20Beijing%20authorities%20are%20willing%20to%20resolve%20antagonisms%20and%20improve%20cross-strait%20relations%2C%20while%20parity%20and%20dignity%20are%20maintained%2C%20we%20are%20willing%20to%20work%20together%20to%20facilitate%20meaningful%20dialogueTsai%20Ing-wen%2C%20Taiwan%20president&amp;hashtags="></a></p>



<p>China says it is responding to “collusion” between Washington and Taipei, angered at growing US support for the self-governed island. Beijing views this a precursor to Taiwan declaring formal independence, a red line for China.Advertisement</p>



<p>Speaking at National Day celebrations, Tsai described the situation in the Taiwan Strait as “quite tense.” This, along with disputes in the South China Sea, a China-India border conflict and China’s crackdown in Hong Kong, showed democracy and peace in the region were facing big challenges, she said.</p>



<p>If Beijing can heed Taiwan’s voice and jointly facilitate reconciliation and peaceful dialogue, regional tension can surely be resolved, she added.</p>



<p>“As long as the Beijing authorities are willing to resolve antagonisms and improve cross-strait relations, while parity and dignity are maintained, we are willing to work together to facilitate meaningful dialogue,” Tsai said.</p>



<p>There was no immediate reaction from China, which cut off a formal talks mechanism in 2016 after she first won office.Advertisementhttps://978719091b5ef461c60b5352c143aebd.safeframe.googlesyndication.com/safeframe/1-0-37/html/container.html</p>



<p>Tsai said she was committed to maintaining stability in the Taiwan Strait, but that this was the responsibility of both sides.</p>



<p>Still, she has made strengthening Taiwan’s armed forces a priority, and said she would keep pushing this, upholding the principle of neither seeking war nor fearing it.</p>



<p>“Our commitment to our sovereignty and democratic values will not change, but we will also maintain strategic flexibility and be responsive to changes,” she said, without elaborating.</p>



<p>The United States has been pushing Taiwan to modernise its military so they can become a “porcupine”, hard for China to attack. Washington, like most countries, has no formal diplomatic ties with Taipei, though it is its strongest global backer.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/index.php/2020/10/10/taiwan-president-calls-for-meaningful-dialogue-with-china/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
